《小鬼当家》
我的行李呢？
Where's my suitcase?
谁偷了吹风机？
Who stole the hair dryer?
哎 小姐
Miss. Young lady!
对不起 小姐们
Excuse me. Girls!
小家伙 嗨
Hey, little fella. Hey!
对不起 小姐们
Excuse me, girls. Girls!
哎 胖子！
Hey, big fella!
帮我整理客厅的床
Help me make the beds in the living room.
下来这里！
Come on down here!
小家伙！
Hey, son!
胖子！小家伙！
Big fella. Hey, little guy! Little guy!
彼得的哥哥和他的全家 现在都在这儿
Pete's brother and his family are here.
翠丝要去蒙特利尔度假
Trish is going to Montreal.
蒙特利尔？噢 她家人在那里
Montreal? Oh, her family's there.
- 我们也放假了 - 你们什么时候走？
- Then we're off. - When?
- 明天就走 - 你是不是还没有准备好？
- Tomorrow. - You're not ready, are you?
法兰克叔叔不让我看电影…
Uncle Frank won't let me watch the movie…
可是他让大孩子看
…but the big kids can.
为什么我就不能看呢？
Why can't I?
我正在讲电话
I'm on the phone.
你们什么时候回来？
When do you come back?
这部电影又不是限制级 他真讨厌
It's not even rated R. He's just being a jerk.
凯文 要是法兰克叔叔说不能看…
Kevin, if Uncle Frank says no…
那一定是烂片
…then it must be really bad.
不 我们要把狗送去狗舍里… 嘿 下去！
No, we put the dog in the kennel… Hey, get off!
凯文 出去！
Kevin, out of the room.
挂了电话再来赶我出去啊
Hang up the phone and make me, why don't you?
死孩子
This kid.
你有没有买电流转换器之类的东西？
Did you pick up a voltage adapter thing?
没有 我没闲时间买那个
No, I didn't have time.
- 那我到法国用什么刮胡子？- 那就留山羊胡啊
- Then how do I shave in France? - Grow a goatee.
爸 他们什么事都不让我做
Dad, nobody'll let me do anything.
我找点事给你做 把这里的小东西都收好
I've got something, pick up those Micro Machines that are all over.
你莱丝莉婶婶脖子差点断掉
Aunt Leslie almost broke her neck.
他又玩热熔胶枪了
He was playing with the glue gun again.
我们谈过这个了吧
We talked about that.
我有把房子烧掉过吗？没有
Did I burn down the joint? I don't think so.
我只是用鱼钩做了一个装饰品
I made ornaments out of fish hooks.
- 是用我的新鱼钩做的吧？- 我又不能用旧鱼钩做
- My new fish hooks? - I can't make them out of old ones…
有干的蚯蚓肠子粘在上面
…with dry worm guts stuck on them.
- 彼得 - 走吧 凯文 出去吧
- Peter. - Come on, Kevin. Out.
你有电流转换器吗？
Do you guys have a voltage adapter?
这里有一个
Here's a voltage adapter!
你越来越重了 快去收拾你的行李吧
God, you're getting heavy! Go pack your suitcase.
收拾我的行李？
Pack my suitcase?
- 洗发精在哪里？- 我又不住这里
- Where's the shampoo? - I don't live here.
这房子里有这么多人住居然连瓶洗发精都没有
This many people here and no shampoo.
- 你父母在家吗？- 他们不住在这里
- Are your folks home? - They don't live here.
- 崔西 是你叫的披萨吗？- 是巴兹叫的
- Tracy, did you order the pizza? - Buzz did.
对不起 你的父母在这里吗？
Excuse me. Are your parents here?
我父母住在巴黎
My parents live in Paris.
- 你好！- 你好！
- Hi! - Hi!
- 你父母在家吗？- 在啊
- Are your parents home? - Yeah.
- 他们住在这吗？- 不
- Do they live here? - No.
全是孩子 没有父母
No. Why should they? All kids, no parents.
这是孤儿院还是什么地方
Probably a fancy orphanage.
我不知道怎么收拾行李 我这一辈子还从来没有收拾过行李呢
I don't know how to pack a suitcase. I've never done it once.
- 厉害啊 - 梅根也是这么说的
- Tough. - That's what Megan said.
- 我说什么？- 你说他厉害
- What did I say? - You told him, "Tough."
这家伙嘀咕行李半天了 我能说什么？
The dope was whining about a suitcase. What was I supposed to say?
恭喜他 恭喜他是白痴吗？
"Congratulations, you're an idiot"?
- 我才不是白痴！- 是吗？
- I'm not an idiot! - Really?
你根本不会照顾自己！什么事都要别人帮你做
You're helpless! We have to do everything for you.
- 她说得没错 凯文 - 得了吧 讨厌 我比你小那么多
- She's right, Kev. - Excuse me, puke-breath. I'm small.
还不会收拾行李呢
I don't know how to pack.
- 希望你别放乱七八糟的东西在行李里 - 闭嘴 琳妮
- I hope you didn't just pack crap. - Shut up, Linnie.
那我应该带什么东西
Do you know what I should pack?
巴兹叫你多带些卫生纸和水
Buzz told you, cheek-face. Toilet paper and water.
你干嘛这么担心？
What are you so worried about?
你知道 不管怎么样 妈会帮你收拾东西的
You know Mom's gonna pack your stuff, anyway.
你就是法语中说的那种「无能之辈」
You're what the French call les incompetents.
什么？
What?
投弹啦！躲开！
Bombs away!
看来你得和富勒睡一张沙发床了
P.S. You have to sleep on the hide-a-bed with Fuller.
他睡前只要喝点东西就会尿床
If he has something to drink, he'll wet the bed.
这房子里这么多人 真烦死人了！
This house is so full of people it makes me sick!
等我长大了就结婚 我要自己一个人住！
When I grow up and get married, I'm living alone!
听见没有？我要自己住！
Did you hear me? I'm living alone!
我要自己住！
I'm living alone!
谁来喂你的蜘蛛啊？
Who's gonna feed your spider?
他刚刚吃了很多老鼠内脏 应该能顶几个星期
He just ate a load of mice guts. He'll be good for a couple weeks.
法国妞是不是真的不刮腋毛？
Is it true French babes don't shave their pits?
有些妞是不刮
Some don't.
法国有裸体海滩
But they got nude beaches.
冬季没有
Not in the winter.
巴兹？
Buzz?
你不会敲门啊？浑蛋
Don't you know how to knock, phlegm-wad?
我在你的房里睡觉好吗？我不要和富勒一起睡
Can I sleep here? I don't want to sleep with Fuller.
他喝点水就尿床
If he drinks, he'll wet the bed.
就算你长在我的屁股上 我也不会让你睡在我的房间里
I wouldn't let you sleep in my room if you were growing on my ass.
看外面 是老家伙马利
Check it out. Old man Marley.
他是谁？
Who's he?
听说过南弯雪锹杀手吗？
You ever heard of the South Bend Shovel Slayer?
- 没有 - 就是他
- No. - That's him.
在1958年 他用铲雪锹把他家人和半数以上的邻居…
In '58 he murdered his whole family and half the people on his block…
打死了
…with a snow shovel.
自从那次事件以后 他就一直隐居在这里
Been hiding out in this neighborhood ever since.
他是杀人犯 警察干嘛不抓他？
If he's the shovel slayer, how come the cops don't arrest him?
证据不足 无法定罪
Not enough evidence to convict.
警察从没有找到过尸体
They never found the bodies.
可是这里每个人都知道 是他干的
Everyone around here knows he did it.
我看他还会杀人
It'll just be a matter of time…
只不过是迟早的问题
…before he does it again.
那他现在干嘛？
What's he doing now?
他每天夜里都在街上…
He walks up and down the streets every night…
走来走去
…salting the sidewalks.
他也许是在做好事吧
Maybe he's just trying to be nice.
不可能
No way.
看那垃圾桶是不是装满了盐？
See that garbage can full of salt?
被杀了的人就放在那里面
That's where he keeps his victims.
然后盐就把尸体
The salt turns the bodies…
变成了木乃伊
…into mummies.
木乃伊
Mummies!
别让他看见！
Look out!
（小尼罗披萨二十分钟内送达 不然免费）
小朋友你们好吗？很好吧？
How you kids doing? Good?
今天这儿有好多玩的 对不对？
Lot of action around here today, huh?
去度假吗？
Going on vacation?
你们去哪儿？
Where you going?
听到我说的吗？要去旅行吗？
You hear me, or what? Going on a trip?
你们去哪啊孩子？
Where you going, kid?
一共是122块半
Okay, that's $122.50.
这不是我叫的 小子 我不住这
Not from me, kid. I don't live here.
你是来过节的吧？
You just around for the holidays?
算是吧
You could say that.
- 披萨送来了！- 是的
- Pizza's here! - There you go.
一共122块半
That's $122.50.
这是我弟弟的家 他会给你钱的
It's my brother's house. He'll get it.
哎 听我说…
Hey, listen…
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hi. - Hi.
- 你是麦卡利斯特先生吗？- 我是
- Are you Mr. McCallister? - Yeah.
是住这的麦卡利斯特先生吗？
The Mr. McCallister who lives here?
好 披萨一共122块半
Good, because somebody owes me $122.50.
- 我想跟你谈谈 - 要抓我还是怎样？
- I'd like a word with you, sir. - Am I under arrest or something?
一般入室抢劫多在节日期间发生
No, no, no. There's always a lot of burglaries around the holidays.
所以我们要对周围进行检查
We're checking the neighborhood.
看看大家是不是采取了适当的防范措施
to see if the proper precautions are taken.
我们有装自动照明计时器 每个门也都装有门锁
We have automatic timers for our lights, locks for our doors.
这些都是每户人家可以做得到的
That's about as well as anybody can do.
- 你喝了蛋酒之类的东西吗？- 走吧
- Did you get some eggnog? - Come on.
- 吃东西去 - 快点
- Let's eat. - Come on.
- 蛋酒？- 吃披萨啦
- Eggnog? - Pizza!
- 你是要走了吗？- 吃披萨啦！
- Are you gonna be leaving… - Pizza!
自己拿餐巾纸 自己倒饮料啊
Grab a napkin and pour your own drinks.
- 圣诞老人也要过海关检查吗？- 我们几点要上床睡觉？
- Does Santa go through customs? - What time do we have to go to bed?
要早点睡 明早8点出发
Early. We're leaving at 8 a.m. on the button.
喝牛奶啊 走之前我们要喝完所有的牛奶
I hope you're all drinking milk. I want to get rid of it.
- 卖披萨的要122块半加小费 - 光是披萨？
- Pizza boy needs $122.50, plus tip. - For pizza?
十个乘12块
Ten pizzas times 12 bucks.
- 你身上有带钱 - 我带的是旅行支票
- You've got money. - Traveler's checks.
算了 法兰克 我们有现金
Forget it, Frank. We have cash.
你的那种旅行支票 在法国可能不能用
You probably got the checks that don't work in France.
有起司披萨吗？
Did anyone order me a plain cheese?
有 不过你要是要的话…
Yeah. But if you want any…
等人家吐出来吧 因为已经没有了
…somebody's gonna have to barf it up because it's gone.
富勒 慢慢来 别猛灌
Fuller! Go easy on the Pepsi.
凯文 快拿个盘子来接着！
Kev! Kev, get a plate.
- 护照！- 小心点！
- Passports! - Watch it!
快把护照拿走
No, no. Get these passports out of here.
你没事吧？快过来 你没事吧？
Are you okay, honey? Come here. Are you all right?
你发什么神经啊你？
What is the matter?
是他先惹我的 他故意吃了我的披萨
He started it! He ate my pizza on purpose.
他知道我讨厌香肠和橄榄口味…
He knows I hate sausage and olives…
看你干的好事！你这个小浑蛋！
Look what you did, you little jerk!
给我上楼
Get upstairs now.
为什么？
Why?
你真是个衰鬼
You're such a disease.
- 闭上你的嘴巴 - 凯文 上楼去！
- Shut up! - Kevin, upstairs!
- 说晚安 凯文 - 晚安 凯文
- Say good night, Kevin. - "Good night, Kevin."
为什么我待遇这么差
Why do I get treated like scum?
对不起 家里乱糟糟的
I'm sorry. This house is just crazy.
家里又多了些孩子
We've got all these extra kids running around.
我哥哥也从俄亥俄州过来了 真是乱上加乱
My brother's in from Ohio. It's nuts.
怎么不多送些起司披萨来？
How come you didn't bring more cheese pizzas?
- 这么多小费 - 谢谢
- Nice tip. Thanks. - Thanks.
亲朋好友都来过节啦？
Having a reunion?
我先生的哥哥被调到巴黎工作 孩子们还留在这里上学
My husband's brother transferred to Paris. His kids are still here.
他想他家人了 所以叫我们全都去巴黎过节
He missed the family, so he invited us to Paris…
我们就可以全在一起了
…so we'll be together.
- 你们要去巴黎吗？- 是的 明天就动身
- You're taking a trip to Paris? - Yes, we leave tomorrow morning.
太好了 真是太好了
Excellent. Excellent.
真是抱歉 这孩子闹别扭
If you'll excuse me, this one's a little out of sorts.
不用招呼我 我今天已经跟你丈夫聊过了
Don't worry about me. I spoke to your husband.
也不用担心你家了 有我们呢
And don't worry about your home. It's in good hands.
这房子里有15个人 就是你老惹麻烦
Fifteen people in this house, and only you have to make trouble.
我是个受气包
I'm getting dumped on.
你是个淘气包 好了 上楼去吧
You're the only one acting up. Now get upstairs.
我不是已经在楼上了吗 白痴
I am upstairs, dummy!
还上三楼呀？
The third floor?
- 上去吧 - 上面太恐怖了
- Go. - It's scary up there.
富勒马上就会上去的
Fuller'll be up in a while.
我不要和他一起睡 他尿床
I don't want to sleep with Fuller. He wets the bed.
他会把我浇湿 我知道他会
He'll pee all over me. I know it.
我让他睡别的地方
We'll put him somewhere else.
对不起
I'm sorry.
时间不早了 快上楼睡吧
It's too late. Get upstairs.
家里的每个人都讨厌我！
Everyone in this family hates me!
那你应该叫圣诞老人帮你换个新家
Then ask Santa for a new family.
我才不要什么新家呢！我什么家都不要！家太让人讨厌了
I don't want a new family. I don't want any family. Families suck!
就待在上面吧！今天晚上我再也不要看见你了
Stay up there. I don't want to see you again tonight.
我以后一辈子也不想再看见你了
I don't want to see you for the rest of my life.
还有其他人我也都不想再看到
I don't want to see anybody else either.
你最好不是认真的
I hope you don't mean that.
要是明天早上醒来家没了 你会伤心的
You'd feel pretty sad if you woke up and didn't have a family.
不 我才不会
No, I wouldn't.
那你再讲一次啊 说不定真会发生呢
Then say it again. Maybe it'll happen.
我想永远再也不要看见你们这些讨厌鬼！
I hope I never see any of you jerks again!
我希望他们全都消失
I wish they would all just disappear.
- 人在哪？- 谁知道？她说了8点整的
- Where are they? - I don't know. She said 8 sharp.
彼得！
Peter!
- 睡过头了！- 睡过头了！
- We slept in! - We slept in!
嗨 我是米奇·墨菲 住在对面
Hi, I'm Mitch Murphy. I live across the street.
你们要出远门吗？
You guys going out of town?
我们要去佛罗里达
We're going to Florida.
其实我们得先去密苏里接我奶奶
Well, first we're going to Missouri to pick up my grandma.
麦卡利斯特先生全家是要去法国
You know the McCallisters are going to France?
那里冷吗？
Do you know if it's cold?
- 这些车费油吗？- 小子 不知道 闪开！
- Do these vans get good mileage? - Kid, I don't know. Hit the road!
先点一下人头 然后叫他们全上车
Do a head count. Get everyone in the vans.
护照和飞机票在哪里？
Where are the passports?
在微波炉里烘干
I put them in the microwave to dry.
这车能跑多快？是自排的吗？
How fast does this go? Does it have automatic transmission?
有四轮驱动吗？
Does it have 4-wheel drive?
我说过了 小子 别烦我 快闪！
Look, I told you before, kid. Don't bother me. Now, beat it!
在车前面排好队！
Line up in front of the van.
排好了 别说话！
Line up and shut up!
安静点！我要点人数了
Shut up! I gotta take a head count.
一 二 三…
One, two, three…
十一 九十二 十二
Eleven, nity-two, twelve…
巴兹 少耍白痴了
Buzz, don't be a moron.
六 七 八…
Six, seven, eight…
九 十 十一
…nine, 10, 11.
好了 一半人上那辆车 另一半上这辆车
Okay, half in this van, half in this one. Let's go.
旅途愉快！从法国带点东西回来给我
Have a good trip. Bring me back something French.
我们绝对赶不上飞机了 剩下不到45分钟了
There's no way we'll make this plane. It leaves in 45 minutes.
多往好处想
Think positive!
想有什么用 还是实际点
You be positive. I'll be realistic.
你家的电线修好了
Ma'am. Ma'am. Excuse me, your power is fixed…
但是你家的电话线绕得乱七八糟的 要好几天才能整理好
…but the phones are a mess. It'll take a couple of days to fix.
- 特别是在过节期间 - 谢谢
- Especially around the holidays. - Thanks.
点过人数没有？
Did you count heads?
11个 包括我
Eleven, including me.
5个男孩 6个女孩 家长有4个 2个司机
Five boys, six girls, four parents, two drivers,
还有梨树上的一只鹌鹑
and a partridge in a pear tree.
飞机等一下！
Hold the plane!
- 我们错过班机了吗？- 刚好赶上
- Did we miss it? - You just made it.
经济舱座位随便坐
Single seats only in coach. Take whatever's free.
我要坐窗边！
I get a window seat!
- 孩子们到经济舱 我们坐这 - 4号A座 B座
- Kids are in coach, we're first class. - Seats Four A and B.
4号A座 B座 把大衣给我吧
Four A and B. I'll take your coats.
- 请系好安全带 - 给我来杯香槟
- Fasten your seat belts. - Champagne, please.
- 是免费的吧？- 是的 先生
- It's free, isn't it? - Oh, yes.
我们还好赶上了
We made it.
真不敢相信 最好没有忘了什么东西
Do you believe it? Hope we didn't forget anything.
妈？
Mom?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 这是真的 真水晶做的 - 所以呢？
- That's real. That's real crystal. - Yeah, so?
- 快放进你的皮包里 - 这样不行 法兰克
- Put them in your purse. - Frank, I can't do that.
快放进你的皮包里
Just… Put them in your purse!
好的 倒满 倒满
Yeah. Fill it up. Fill it up.
请倒满
Fill it up, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
孩子们坐经济舱 我们坐头等舱 你不会觉得不好意思吗？
Don't you feel like a heel, flying first class with the kids in coach?
孩子们很好啊
No. The kids are fine.
我小的时候唯一一次的旅行
The only time I ever flew as a kid.
坐的还是家庭旅行车 当然不是去法国
was in the station wagon, not to France.
我们那时候常去罗拉婶婶和亚瑟叔叔家玩
We had to go to Aunt Laura and Uncle Arthur's.
孩子们都很好 他们在享受生活 都很愉快
Kids are okay. They're having the time of their lives.
有人吗？
Hello?
妈
Mom?
爸？
Dad?
妈？爸？
Mom? Dad?
你们都去哪里了？
Where are you guys?
巴兹？
Buzz?
梅根？
Megan?
喂！
Hello?
罗德？
Rod?
法兰克叔叔？
Uncle Frank?
法兰克叔叔 是开玩笑吗？
Uncle Frank, is this a joke?
梅根？琳妮？
Megan? Linnie?
你们在玩吧？
Is this a joke?
是我乱想
It's only my imagination.
就是我乱想的
Only my imagination.
车子还在这里 他们没有去机场啊
The cars are still here. They didn't go to the airport!
我让全家人消失了！
I made my family disappear.
「你完全无法照顾自己」
You're completely helpless.
凯文… 你就是法语中说的那种「无能之辈」
You know, Kevin, you're what the French call les incompetents.
「凯文 我要把你喂给我的大蜘蛛」
Kevin, I'm going to feed you to my tarantula.
「凯文 你真是个衰鬼」
Kevin, you are such a disease.
「这房子里有15个人 就是你老惹麻烦」
There are 15 people, and you're the only one who has to make trouble.
「瞧你干的好事 你这个小浑蛋！」
Look what you did, you little jerk!
我让全家人消失了！
I made my family disappear.
我自由了
I'm free!
都不穿衣服 真恶心！
No clothes on anybody. Sickening!
酷！鞭炮！留着以后玩
Cool! Firecrackers! I'll save these for later.
巴兹 我在翻你的东西
Buzz, I'm going through all your private stuff.
还不快出来收拾我！
You better come out and pound me!
巴兹的女朋友 好恶
Buzz, your girlfriend! Woof!
（邪恶天使）
谁呀？
Who is it?
是我 小蛇 东西到手了
It's me, Snakes. I got the stuff.
放在台阶上 然后滚蛋
Leave it on the doorstep and get the hell out.
可以 强尼 但钱呢？
All right, Johnny, but what about my money?
要钱吗？
What money?
老大说有我的一份
A.C. said you had some dough for me.
是吗？该给多少？
Is that a fact? How much do I owe you?
老大说过 十分之一
A.C. said 10 percent.
可惜老大说的不算了
Too bad A.C. ain't in charge no more.
我边吃零食边看烂电影
Guys, I'm eating junk and watching rubbish!
还不快出来阻止我！
You better come out and stop me!
他洗完澡后会打电话给你的
He'll call you when he gets out.
嘿
Hey.
告诉你要给你什么
I'll tell you what I'll give you.
我数十下…
I'm gonna give you to the count of 10…
你这个杂种…
…to get your ugly, yellow…
赶快滚蛋
…no-good keister off my property…
不然就请你吃子弹
…before I pump your guts full of lead.
好好 对不起 我马上走
All right, I'm sorry. I'm going.
一 二…十！
One, two…10.
不用找了 畜生！
Keep the change, you filthy animal.
妈！
Mom!
怎么了？
What's the matter?
亲爱的？
Honey?
- 我有种怪怪的感觉 - 是什么呢？
- I have a terrible feeling. - About what?
好像有什么事我们没做
That we didn't do something.
你有这感觉是因为我们走得太急了
You feel that way because we left in a hurry.
- 我们该做的都做了 - 我关咖啡壶了吗？
- We took care of everything. - Did I turn off the coffee?
没有
No.
是我关的
I did.
你有没有锁门？
Did you lock up?
锁了
Yeah.
车库门关了吗？
Did you close the garage?
这个我没关
That's it.
我把车库门忘了 就这一件事
I forgot to close the garage. That's it.
不 不是这件事
No, that's not it.
我们还会忘记什么事呢？
What else could we be forgetting?
是凯文！
Kevin!
机长能做的都做了 你家的电话就是不通
The captain's doing all he can. Your phones are out of order.
飞机一落地我们就打电话 我想不会有什么事的
We'll call when we land. I'm sure it's okay.
真可怕 太可怕了
Horrible. Horrible.
太可怕了
Just horrible.
我们怎么会这样呢？怎么会忘记他了呢？
How could we do this? We forgot him.
我们没忘记他 就是没点对人数
We didn't forget him, we just miscounted.
我算是怎样的母亲啊？
What kind of mother am I?
你听了也许会好过点 我连我的眼镜都忘记带了
If it makes you feel any better, I forgot my reading glasses.
光这一条街上 就有五户人家出去度假
Five families gone on one block alone.
都是他们亲口跟我说的
They all told me from their own mouths.
真是天赐良机
It's almost too easy.
我们看看
Check it out:
所有家里没人的房子
All the houses with nobody home…
都装了灯光自动计时器
…have automatic timers on their lights.
但是我把所有的数字都搞到手了 看这个…
But I got it all figured out. Watch this.
664号灯马上…
Number 664 will be going on right about…
就要亮！
…now.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
672号…
Number 672…
现在亮！
…right now.
等等 等等
Wait a minute.
671号…
671…
亮！
…now.
就是这一家 马文 是个金库
And that's the one, Marvin. That's the silver tuna.
真的搞大了
It's very G.
大吧 啊？
Very G, huh? It's loaded.
屋里有好多高级货
It's got lots of top-flight goods.
- 有音响 录影机 - 玩具
- Stereos, VCRs… - Toys?
可能有些精品珠宝首饰
Probably looking at some very fine jewelry.
或许还有现钞
Possible cash horde.
有价证券什么的
Odd marketable securities.
谁知道呢 反正是个金库
Who knows? It's a gem.
拿好你的铁橇
Grab your crowbar.
铁橇真好用
Crowbars up.
走哪边？
Which way?
我们绕到后面到地下室去
We'll go around back, down the basement.
- 你不是说他们都走了吗？- 他们是今天早上走的
- You said they were gone. - They were gonna leave today.
快离开这吧
Let's get out of here.
我们得用一下电话
We have to use the phone, please.
事情很急 我们真的非常需要打这个电话
It's an emergency. We really have to make a call.
拜托你！我们的弟弟单独一个人在家里
Please! Our brother's home alone.
把电话给我！
Give us the phone!
对不起！谢谢
I'm sorry. Thank you.
我打电话给警察 你去订一下回家的飞机票
I'm calling the police. Book us a flight home.
拿些零钱 打电话给你认识的人
Get change out of here. Call everybody you know.
这是我的通讯录 打电话给住在我们街上的人
Here's my address book. You and Frank call everyone on our street.
可能有人能帮我们
Maybe somebody can help us.
喂？她等一下回你电话
Hello? Hello? Oh, she'll have to call you back.
真可笑 只有胆小鬼才躲在床底下
This is ridiculous. Only a wimp would be hiding under a bed.
我可不是胆小鬼 我现在是一家之主了
And I can't be a wimp. I'm the man of the house.
我不会再害怕了
Hey, I'm not afraid anymore!
我说了 我不会害怕了！
I said, I'm not afraid anymore!
都听见了吗？我再也不害怕了
Do you hear me? I'm not afraid anymore.
警察局
Village police department.
我现在在巴黎 我儿子现在独自在家
I'm calling from Paris. I have a son who's home alone.
所以我想请你们派个人 去我家看看
I'd like somebody to go there. Tell him that we're coming home to get him.
我帮你转到家庭危机解救中心
Okay, let me connect you with Family Crisis Intervention.
不 这不是家庭纠纷
No it's not a family crisis.
别挂
Hold on.
拉瑞 接一下电话 有位神经质女士
Larry, can you pick up? There's some hyper lady on hold.
- 几号线？罗丝 - 2号
- What line, Rose? - Two.
家庭危机解救中心 我是鲍沙警官
Family Crisis Intervention, Sergeant Balzak.
我现在在巴黎 我儿子独自在家
I'm calling from Paris. I have a son who's home alone.
这孩子家里有没有酒鬼 对他使用过暴力？
Has the child been involved in violence with a drunk family member?
没有！
No!
他在家发生过意外吗？
Has he been involved in a household accident?
我不知道 希望他没有
I don't know. I hope not.
这孩子吃了有毒的东西 还是有什么硬东西卡在喉咙里了？
Has the child ingested any poison or is an object lodged in his throat?
就是他单独一人在家里！我想请个人到我家里…
No, he's home alone! I'd like somebody to go over to the house…
看一下他有没有事！
…and see if he's all right.
你想让我们到你家去 就是看一下你的孩子？
You want us to go to your house, just to check on him.
没错！
Yes!
那我帮你转接到警察局
Let me connect you to the police.
刚刚就是他们把我转接到你这里的
They just transferred me.
- 罗丝？神经质在2线 - 等等
- Rose! Hyper on 2. - Hang on.
- 等一下 - 请等一下 别挂电话
- Hold on, please. - No, please don't hang up. Please!
谁打通了？
Any luck?
没有
No.
- 我们一个人也没找到 - 莱丝莉？
- I couldn't get anybody. - Leslie?
都是电话录音
Nothing but a bunch of answering machines.
谁来接电话吧！快接电话！
Somebody pick up. Pick up!
嗨 女士 又是你
Oh, hi, ma'am. It's you again.
我现在在巴黎 我儿子现在独自在家
I'm calling from Paris. I have a son who's home alone, and I…
我们派一个警官到你家去看一下你儿子吧
We'll send a policeman over to your house to check on your son.
家里没有人 房子看起来很安全
There's no one home. The house looks secure.
让他们再数数孩子
Tell them to count their kids again.
你不能换掉一个乘客或者…
You can't bump somebody or ask or…
我真的不能那么做
There's no way I can do that.
你能不能问问看？
Isn't there a way if you ask somebody?
这是一件紧急事件…
If you said it's an emergency…
可是我不能要求别人
I cannot ask them.
他们要派警官到家里
A policeman's going over to the house.
很好 可是机位全都满了
Well, that's a relief. Everything here is booked.
没有去芝加哥的航班了吗？
Nothing to Chicago?
芝加哥 纽约 那什维尔都满了
There's nothing to Chicago, New York, Nashville.
- 私人飞机呢？- 对不起 我们没有这个业务
- What about a private plane? - Sorry. We don't do that.
他们现在能做的就是 为我们订星期五早上的机位
The only thing is a booking for us on Friday morning.
星期五？还有两天
Friday morn… That's two days away.
孩子们都累了 你也累坏了
The kids are exhausted and so are you.
我们待在机场实在没有什么事能做了
There's nothing we can do.
我们先去罗伯家 在那里我们再给警察局打电话
I say we go over to Rob's, and that way we can call the police again.
我不会离开机场的 除非坐上飞机
I'm not leaving here unless it's on an airplane.
夫人 我们就是要尽一切可能帮助乘客
Madame, we are doing everything we can.
如果你留在机场候补 或许能碰上空位
If you want to stay at the airport, maybe we can get you on standby.
是有这种可能的
It is a possibility that a seat will open up.
- 这下行了吧 - 好吧 我等着
- Is that okay? - Yes. I'll wait.
- 我会想你的 - 再见
- Bye. I'll miss you, honey. - Bye.
别把你自己搞丢了
Don't you get lost.
拜拜
Goodbye.
洗澡 擦香皂 全身上下都洗洗
I took a shower, washing every body part with actual soap.
手指缝…
Including all my major crevices…
脚指缝 还有肚脐
…between my toes and in my belly button…
虽然从来没洗过 不过感觉还不错
…which I never did before but enjoyed.
像大人那样用洗发精还有润发乳洗头
I washed my hair with adult formula shampoo and used cream rinse.
好像没有牙刷了 一会儿出去买一枝
I can't find my toothbrush, so I'll pick one up today.
没什么事了 还满像样子的嘛
Other than that, I'm in good shape.
好耶！巴兹存的零用钱
All right! Buzz's life savings.
我还以为墨菲全家都去佛罗里达了
I thought the Murphys went to Florida.
你可真是天下名偷
You're one of the great cat burglars of the world.
你能不能小声一点？
You think you can keep it down a little in there?
家中无人 有事请留话
You've reached the Murphys. Please leave a message after the beep.
我是彼得·麦卡利斯特 现在在我哥巴黎的公寓里
This is Peter McCallister again. We're in Paris at my brother's.
我现在把这里的电话号码留给你 国码是33
Let me give you the number here. The country code is 33.
区码是14 电话号码是694876
The area code is 14 and the number is 694-876…
- 嘿 哈利！- 干嘛？
- Hey, Harry. - Yeah?
昨晚我们去的那家 是彼得的家吗？
That house we ran last night, was that the McCallister's?
是啊
Yeah.
- 打电话到巴黎给我 - 你说的对 他们早走了
- Call me in Paris. - You're right. They're gone.
- 我就知道他们不在 - 今晚搞定那个金库
- I knew they were. - Silver tuna tonight.
能帮你什么吗？
How may I help you?
这种牙刷是不是美国牙医协会认可的？
Is this toothbrush approved by the American Dental Association?
不知道
Well, I don't know.
- 上面没有说明 - 请你查一下好吗？
- It doesn't say, hon. - Can you please find out?
- 贺伯！- 什么事？
- Herb. - Yeah?
我这里有人对牙刷有疑问
I got a question here about a toothbrush.
你知不知道这种牙刷有没有经过牙医协会认可？
Do you know, is this brush approved by the American Dental Association?
不知道
I don't know.
到这来付钱
Oh, hon, you pay for that here.
等一下 你得付钱
Wait, you have to pay for that.
孩子 孩子
Son! Son! Hey!
吉米 快抓住那孩子
Jimmy, stop that boy!
嘿！
Hey!
抓小偷！
Shoplifter!
哎 小子！
Hey! Hey, kid!
给我过来！
Come back here!
给我站住！
Stop it, will you?
回来
Come here.
我是罪犯
I'm a criminal.
有什么好笑的？
What's so funny?
笑什么？
你笑什么啊？
Why are you laughing?
又犯老毛病了吧？
You did it again.
又没关水了对吧？
You left the water running.
你这是什么毛病？我早跟你说过不要这样
Why do you do that? I told you not to do it.
- 这叫雁过留声人过留名 - 雁过留声人过留名
- It's our calling card. - Calling card.
天下所有的大盗都要留下他们的标记
All the great ones leave their mark.
我们就是「水盗」
We're the Wet Bandits.
你有病你知不知道？真的有病
You're sick, you know? You're really sick.
- 我没病 - 你有
- I'm not sick. - Yes, you are.
这么搞就是有病
It's a sick thing to do.
- 不许再这么搞了！- 不要教我怎么搞
- We don't need that. - Don't tell me…
我爱怎么搞就怎么搞
I can do it if I want to.
我没有病！小心点！
It's not sick. Hey, watch out!
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
走路得小心
You gotta watch out for traffic.
- 对不起 - 气死人
- Sorry. - Damn.
圣诞老人可不去殡仪馆送礼物
Santy don't visit the funeral homes, buddy.
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
你怎么了？
What's the matter?
我不喜欢他的眼神
I don't like the way that kid looked at me.
- 以前你见过他吗？- 我这个星期见了几百个小孩子
- Ever seen him before? - I saw a hundred kids this week.
我们看看他去哪家？
Let's see what house he goes into.
他干嘛走那么快？
Why's he going faster?
我跟你说过不对劲的嘛
I told you something's wrong.
他的眼神很怪 他跑什么？
He looked at me weird. Why would he run?
也许他进教堂了
Maybe he went in the church.
- 我可不到里面去 - 我也不去
- I'm not going in there. - Me neither.
离开这吧
Let's get out of here.
我要做好准备 等这些家伙过来
When those guys come back, I'll be ready.
他们回来了吗？
Did they come back?
从巴黎？
From Paris?
我们明天再来 说不定他们就走了
We'll come back tomorrow. Maybe they'll be gone.
我们赶快走吧 别被人看见
We better go before somebody sees us.
看我在厨房找到了什么东西？
Look what I found in the kitchen.
法兰克 那个晚点才能吃
Frank, those are for later.
孩子们 吃小虾子吗？
Do you want a little shrimp, huh?
你会说英语吗？
Do you speak English?
有没有…
Well, is there…
- 找到人了？- 我正在找儿子！
- Did you get anybody? - I am looking for my son!
一个人都找不到
No, I can't find anybody.
全都出去逛街了 一过节不会有人在家
They're all shopping. Nobody's home for the holidays.
别在意
Never mind, forget it.
- 这节过得真无聊 - 怎么了？
- This is so pointless. - What?
我们在这公寓里憋到烂掉
We're here rotting in this apartment.
凯文在家 妈在机场
Kevin's at home. Mom's at the airport.
- 那又怎样？- 你就不担心凯文出事吗？
- So? - You're not worried about Kevin?
我干嘛担心他？他这个讨厌鬼 自己自作自受
Why should I be? He acted like a jerk, and now he caught it in the butt.
但是他还小啊 又没人帮他！你就不想想他可能会吓坏的
He's so little and helpless. Don't you think he's flipped out?
他应该在真实世界里过几天
The trout can use a couple of days in the real world.
你就一点儿都不担心 他可能会发生什么事？
You're not worried something might happen?
不担心 三个理由
No. For three reasons:
第一 我就没这么幸运
A, I'm not that lucky.
第二 我们家里装了烟雾警报器
Two, we have smoke detectors…
最后 我们住在全美国最无聊的街上
…and D, we live in the most boring street in the United States…
也就是最不会发生危险的地方 就这样
…where nothing even remotely dangerous will ever happen. Period.
（请走后门）
谁呀？
Who is it?
小尼罗披萨
It's Little Nero's. I have your pizza.
放在台阶上 然后滚蛋
Leave it on the doorstep and get the hell out.
好吧
Okay.
那我的钱呢？
What about the money?
要钱吗？
What money?
吃披萨是要付钱的 先生
Well, you have to pay for your pizza, sir.
是吗？该给多少？
Is that a fact? How much do I owe you?
11块8毛 先生
That'll be $11.80, sir.
不用找了 畜生！
Keep the change, you filthy animal.
- 小气鬼 - 嘿
- Cheapskate. - Hey.
我数十下
I'm gonna give you to the count of 10…
你这个杂种…
…to get your ugly, yellow…
赶快滚蛋
…no-good keister off my property…
不然就请你吃子弹
…before I pump your guts full of lead.
一 二… 十！
One, two…ten.
这次就我一个人独享起司披萨了
A lovely cheese pizza, just for me.
飞往达拉斯的班机
… to Dallas/Fort Worth.
就要起飞了
American Airlines…
我还有500美元 一个快译通
So we have the $500, the pocket translator…
还有两张头等舱的机票
…the two first-class seats, that's an upgrade…
你的表是真的劳力士吗？
Is that a real Rolex?
- 你看呢？- 假的
- Do you think it is? - No.
谁能看得出来？我这还有个戒指
But who can tell? I also have a ring.
真漂亮！
That is beautiful!
开始登机了
They're boarding.
她愿意出星期五的两张头等舱机票跟我们换
She's offered us two first-class tickets if we go Friday.
外加一个戒指 一只表
Plus a ring, a watch,
一个快译通 还有500美元 还有…
a pocket translator, $500 and…
耳环
The earrings.
她有一大盒子的耳环呢
She's got her own earrings. A whole shoebox full of them.
- 快点 - 那…
- Come on, come on. - No, but…
我很急
I'm desperate.
我求求你们 你也是母亲吧 求你了
I'm begging you. From a mother to a mother. Please!
- 噢 艾德 - 求求你
- Oh, Ed. - Please!
噢 好吧
Oh, all right.
亲爱的圣诞老人 去年我的礼物是个妹妹
"Dear Santa, I got a sister last year.
今年我想要粘土
This year I'd rather have Clay-Doh."
我不是有意的
I didn't mean it.
都回来吧 我不再惹你们了
If you come back, I'll never be a pain in the butt again.
我保证 晚安
I promise. Good night.
微波炉快餐好吃吗？
Are those microwave dinners good?
- 不知道 - 那我试一次好了
- I don't know. - I'll give them a whirl.
给孩子的
For the kids.
等一下 我有折价券
Hold on, I got a coupon for that.
是早上从报纸上剪下来的
It was in the paper this morning.
19块8毛3分
$19.83.
好
Okay.
你自己一个人来的吗？
Are you here by yourself?
女士我才8岁
Ma'am, I'm 8 years old.
你说我会一个人来吗？当然不会
You think I'd be here alone? I don't think so.
你妈妈在哪？
Where's your mom?
- 在车上 - 那你爸爸呢？
- In the car. - Where's your dad?
- 上班 - 你的兄弟姐妹呢？
- He's at work. - What about brothers and sisters?
我是独生子
I'm an only child.
- 你住哪里？- 我不能告诉你
- Where do you live? - I can't tell you.
- 干嘛不告诉我？- 因为我不认识你
- Why not? - Because you're a stranger.
哈啰 凯文
Hello, Kevin!
闭嘴
Shut up!
真搞不懂
I don't get it.
这家现在看上去好像又没人在里面了
It looks like there's nobody's home.
昨晚上满屋子都是人
Last night the place is jumping.
不对劲
Something ain't right.
去看看
Go check it out.
现在吗？
Now?
不是现在还是明天呀？猪脑啊你！去啊
No, tomorrow, egghead! Now! Go ahead.
就现在
"Now? "
妈的！
Shit!
你快滚蛋
Get the hell out of here.
可以 强尼 钱呢？
All right, Johnny. But what about my money?
要钱吗？
What money?
老大说有我的一份
A.C. said you had some dough for me.
是吗？该给多少？
Is that a fact? How much do I owe you?
老大说过 十分之一
A.C. said 10 percent.
可惜老大说的不算了
Too bad A.C. ain't in charge no more.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他在楼上洗澡
He's upstairs, taking a bath.
他洗完澡后会打电话给你的
He'll call you when he gets out.
嘿 告诉你要给你什么 小蛇…
Hey, I tell you what I'm gonna give you, Snakes.
- 小蛇？- 我数十下
- Snakes? - I'll give you to the count of 10…
你这个杂种…
…to get your ugly, yellow, no-good…
赶快滚蛋
…keister off my property…
不然就请你吃子弹
…before I pump your guts full of lead.
好好 强尼 对不起 我马上走
All right, Johnny. I'm sorry. I'm going.
一 二…十！
One, two…ten.
不用找了 畜生！
Keep the change, you filthy animal.
出什么事了？
What happened?
里面不知道是什么人让人打死了
I don't know who, but somebody got blown away.
有人抢了我们的生意 他们就在里面！
Somebody beat us, they're in there.
是两个人
Two of them.
他们正在吵架 一个人拿枪把另一个给干掉了
There was arguing. One blew the other one away.
- 谁？- 不知道
- Who? - I don't know.
我认出他们当中一个人的声音
I recognized one of their voices.
我想我以前听到过小蛇这个名字
I heard that name "Snakes" before.
小蛇？小蛇 我不认识叫小蛇的
Snakes? Snakes. Snakes. I don't know no Snakes.
小蛇 我们还是快走吧！
Snakes. Let's get out of here.
别慌 别慌
Hold it. Hold it.
我们等在这里看看到底是谁干的 这块地盘也是我们的
Let's wait and see who it is. We work this neighborhood too.
说不定警察会问我们…
Suppose the cops finger us for a job…
然后他们问这附近的谋杀案的事
…and they ask us about a murder in the area.
要是能指认出个人不是很好吗？
Won't it be nice to have a face to go with it?
这可是个好主意
That's a good idea.
当然是 小蛇？
Of course it's a good idea. Snakes?
他的名字听起来像是小蛇
He sounded like a snake.
班机全部客满
Everything's full.
班机全部客满？
Everything's full?
没办法 圣诞前夕
I'm very sorry, but it is Christmas Eve.
其他航空公司呢？
What about another airline?
都满了 我可以帮您在饭店订个房间吗？
Nothing available. May I help you get a hotel room?
您可以搭明天下午的航班去芝加哥
Tomorrow we can get you a flight.
我等不了那么长时间
I can't wait that long.
对不起 女士 我们已经尽力了
I'm sorry, ma'am, but we're doing absolutely everything we can.
我挡到你了 对不起 你有地方度假
I'm in your way. I'm sorry. You've places to go.
你有机票 很好 对不起
Got a ticket there, good. Excuse me.
我差不多有60个小时没睡觉了
Look, I have been awake for almost 60 hours.
累得要死 身上又脏兮兮的
I'm tired and I'm dirty.
我从芝加哥到了巴黎 去了达拉斯
I have been from Chicago to Paris, to Dallas to…
这是什么鬼地方？
Where am I?
斯克蓝顿
Scranton.
我急着回家去看我8岁的儿子！
I'm trying to get home to my 8-year-old son.
你却告诉我没有办法？
Now you're telling me it's hopeless?
- 对不起 - 不 不用
- I'm sorry. - No. No way.
这是圣诞节 是充满希望的时候
This is Christmas! The season of perpetual hope.
到跑道上去拦飞机也无所谓…
If I have to get on your runway and hitchhike…
不管花多大代价…
…if it costs me everything I own…
如果需要把灵魂卖给魔鬼…
…if I have to sell my soul to the devil himself…
为了能回家去看我的儿子 我也卖
…I am going to get home to my son.
如果我今天能帮你任何忙…
Ma'am, if there was anything…
那就做吧！
Do it. Do anything.
- 我能帮你订一间的房 - 干嘛？
- I can get you a hotel room. - What?
不好意思 打搅一下行吗？
Can you excuse us for a sec? Can I see you for a second, please?
对不起
Excuse us.
我无意中听到你说的话
You got a little bit of a dilemma.
我们也遇到了危机
We got a crisis ourselves.
允许我自我介绍一下 我叫卡斯·波林斯基
Allow me to introduce myself. Gus Polinski.
中西部波卡音乐之王
Polka King of the Midwest?
听说过肯诺夏舞者吗？
The Kenosha Kickers?
- 嗨 - 你好
- Hi there. - Hi.
没关系 我以为你能认出我们来
That's okay. I thought you might have recognized…
几年前我出了几首曲子 轰动一时
I had a few hits a few years ago. That's why I just…
「波卡 波卡 波卡」
"Polka, Polka, Polka"?
没听过吗？那么「双湖波卡」呢？
No? "Twin Lakes Polka"?
还有「亚犸乎兹亚波卡」
"Yamahoozie Polka, "
就是「亲亲我波卡」？还有「旋转波卡」…
a.k.a."Kiss Me Polka"? "Polka Twist"?
这些都是歌曲吗？
These are songs?
是的 我们这帮人相当受欢迎
Yeah. Yeah, we… Some fairly big hits for us.
特别是在70年代早期
You know, in the early '70s.
我们卖了623张唱片
Yeah, we sold about 623 copies of that.
- 在芝加哥吗？- 不 在希波干市
- In Chicago? - No, Sheboygan.
全市都轰动了
Very big in Sheboygan.
你是说能帮我吗？
Did you say you could help?
我在喃喃自语 我们的航班取消了…
Anyway, I'm rambling on here. Our flight was canceled…
所以我们准备开车去 看到那个穿黄夹克上有标记的人吗？
…so we gotta drive. See the guy in the yellow jacket over there?
是他租给我们一辆漂亮的大车 我们开着去密尔瓦基
He's gonna rent us a nice big van to drive to Milwaukee.
我刚才听你说要去芝加哥？
Now, I heard you had some problems getting to Chicago?
去看你的孩子还是什么？
To see your kid?
我们走的时候把他忘在家里了
My son. He… We left, and he's there.
你要是去芝加哥 我们很高兴可以开车送你去
If you have to get to Chicago, we'll gladly drive you.
正好是去密瓦基的路上
It's on the way to Milwaukee.
- 你们可以送我？- 当然要送
- You'd give me a ride? - Sure, why not?
你还是早点回家看孩子吧
You gotta get home.
- 坐车去芝加哥？- 现在是圣诞节嘛
- A ride to Chicago? - Sure, it's Christmastime.
谢谢你！噢 谢谢！
Thank you. Oh, thank you.
你不介意和波卡流浪艺人一起坐车吧？
You don't mind going with polka bums?
不 不介意
No, I'd love to.
嘿 马文
Hey, Marv. Marv, Marv!
看看
Look at this.
我看我们是让这个小子骗了
I think we're getting scammed by a kindergartner.
爸爸 过来帮帮忙好不好？
Dad, can you come here and help me?
还记得那天我们见到的那个小孩吗？
Remember that kid we saw the other day?
就住这
He lives here.
那要是孩子在家 父母肯定也在家
If the kid's here, the parents got to be.
他可是单独一人在家
He's home alone.
你白痴啊！你要晚上才来吗？
What? You want to come back tonight?
这个孩子在这你也敢来？
Even with the kid here?
我觉得不能这样搞
I don't think that's a good idea.
就是这房子使我们决定要在这个街区动手的
That house is the reason we worked this block.
自从我第一次看到这栋房子 我就想要
Ever since I saw that house, I wanted it.
我们一步步来
Let's take it one step at a time.
先把卡车给腾空了 再吃点饭 九点左右我们再回来
We'll unload the van, get a bite to eat, we'll come back about 9:00.
九点左右
Nine o'clock.
那时候天就黑了
This way it's dark.
对啊 小孩子怕黑
Yeah, kids are scared of the dark.
你也怕黑 你自己知道
You're afraid of the dark too. You know you are.
我不怕黑
No, I'm not.
- 你就是怕！- 不怕不怕不怕！
- Yes, you are. - Not, not, not.
就是怕
You are so.
妈妈 你在哪呢？
Mom, where are you?
你会吹这个吗？
Do you play?
要不要试试看？来嘛 试试 试试
Do you want to try? Go ahead, try it. Try it!
（圣诞老人）
- 对不起 - 什么事？
- Excuse me. - Yeah?
嘿 这双鞋真漂亮！
Hey, nice shoes.
噢 谢谢
Oh, thanks.
圣诞老人还在这吗？我有重要的事要跟他说
Is he still here? It's really important that I see him.
他正要上车呢 你要是跑快点还能赶上他
He's getting in his car. If you hurry, you can catch him.
真该死！居然在圣诞前夕 给圣诞老人开罚单
How low! Giving Kriss Kringle a parking ticket on Christmas Eve!
那下次是什么？难道还要给复活节兔子打狂犬病疫苗吗？
What's next, rabies shots for the Easter Bunny?
圣诞老人 等一下
Santa, hold on.
- 能耽误你一下吗？- 要快一点 圣诞老人快迟到了
- Can I talk to you? - Make it quick. Santa's running late.
我知道你不是真的圣诞老人
I know you're not the real Santa Claus.
你怎么会这样说？我想知道为什么
What makes you say that? Just out of curiosity.
- 我能明白是怎么回事了 - 是的
- I'm old enough to know how it works. - All right.
但是我也知道你在为圣诞老人做事
But I also know you work for him.
- 我想请你帮我传话给他 - 说吧
- I'd like you to give him a message. - Shoot.
我是凯文·麦卡利斯特 住林肯大道671号 要电话号码吗？
Kevin McCallister, 671 Lincoln Blvd. Do you need the phone number?
不用了
No, that's all right.
这件事非常重要
This is extremely important.
请你告诉圣诞老人 今年不要送礼物了
Please tell him instead of presents,
就把我的全家人送回来就行了
I just want my family back.
不要玩具 什么都不要 就要彼得 凯蒂
No toys. Nothing but Peter, Kate,
巴兹 梅根 琳妮 杰夫
Buzz, Megan, Linnie and Jeff.
还有我的婶婶和表兄弟姐妹们
And my aunt and my cousins.
如果有时间的话 还有我的叔叔法兰克 好吗？
And if he has time, my Uncle Frank. Okay?
好的
Okay.
- 我会想办法的 - 谢谢
- I'll see what I can do. - Thanks.
等等！我的小矮人把剩下的棒棒糖给她的男朋友了
Wait. My elf took the last of the candy canes home to her boyfriend.
- 没关系 - 不用 别傻了
- That's okay. - No, don't be silly.
见到圣诞老人的人 一定要得到点东西
Everybody who sees Santa has gotta get something.
在这儿 伸出你的小爪子 拿去
Here, hold out your little paw there. There you go.
- 别吃多了 不然吃不下饭 - 不会的
- Don't spoil your dinner. - I won't.
谢谢
Thanks.
妈的
Son of a…
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
我可以坐下吗？
May I sit down?
我的孙女在那上面
That's my granddaughter.
那个红头发的小女孩
The little red-haired girl.
她和你差不多大 你认识她吗？
She's about your age. You know her?
不认识
No.
你住我隔壁 是吧？
You live next to me, don't you?
你见到我可以跟我打招呼 你不用害怕
You can say hello when you see me. You don't have to be afraid.
城里有很多关于我的传言 但都不是真的 懂吗？
There's a lot of things going around about me, but none of it's true. Okay?
- 你今年有当个乖孩子吗？- 我想有吧
- You've been good this year? - I think so.
敢发誓吗？
You swear to it?
不
No.
只有你觉得自己不好 才会到这个地方来
Yeah. Well, this is the place to be if you're feeling bad about yourself.
- 是吗？- 我是这么想的
- It is? - I think so.
- 你觉得自己不好吗？- 没有
- Are you feeling bad about yourself? - No.
最近我一直惹人厌 尽说些不该说的话
I've been kind of a pain lately. I said some things I shouldn't have.
今年我的表现真的不太好
I really haven't been too good this year.
是的
Yeah.
我满难过的 我真的很爱我的家人
I'm kind of upset because I really like my family.
尽管有时我嘴上说我不爱他们 我甚至心里想过我不爱他们
Even though sometimes I say I don't. Sometimes I even think I don't.
- 你明白了吗？- 差不多吧
- Do you get that? - I think so.
家家都有一本难念的经
How you feel about your family is a complicated thing.
特别是和哥哥的关系
Especially with an older brother.
内心深处虽然总是爱着他们
Deep down, you'll always love them.
但却不知怎样去表现 于是就伤害了他们也伤害了自己
But you can forget that you love them. You can hurt them, they can hurt you.
这跟年纪大小好像没有关系
And that's not just because you're young.
你是不是想知道我到这里的真正原因？
You want to know the real reason why I'm here?
是的
Sure.
我是来听我孙女唱歌的 而今晚我是不能来的
I came to hear my granddaughter sing. I can't come hear her tonight.
你有约会吗？
You have plans?
不是
No.
他们不欢迎我
I'm not welcome.
教堂不欢迎你？
At church?
教堂总是欢迎你的
You're always welcome at church.
是我的儿子不欢迎我
I'm not welcome with my son.
几年前 你们家搬来这个区前…
Years back, before you and your family moved on the block…
我和我儿子大吵了一架
…I had an argument with my son.
他多大了？
How old is he?
他是大人了
He's grown up.
我们都发了火 我说我不想再看见他了
We lost our tempers, and I said I didn't care to see him anymore.
他也是这么说的 从那时起 我们就没讲过话了
He said the same, and we haven't spoken to each other since.
既然你想他 干嘛不打电话给他？
If you miss him, why don't you call him?
我害怕我要是打电话给他 他不会理我
I'm afraid if I call, he won't talk to me.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我也不知道 就是害怕他不理我
I don't know. I'm just afraid he won't.
不是我存心冒犯你 你岁数大了 是不是不该害怕了？
No offense, but aren't you a little old to be afraid?
人一天天变老…
You can be old for a lot of things.
- 但总是会害怕的 - 这倒是
- You're never too old to be afraid. - That's true.
我一直害怕地下室
I was afraid of our basement.
太黑 总觉得有些怪东西在下面 里面的味道也怪怪的
It's dark. There's weird stuff down there, and it smells funny.
这样的事烦我好多年了
That sort of thing. It's bothered me for years.
地下室给人的感觉都是那个样子
Basements are like that.
后来我壮着胆子下去洗衣服
I made myself go down to do some laundry…
发觉并不那么可怕
…and I found out it's not so bad.
开始我一直很害怕 后来把灯一打开 就什么事都没了
I worried about it, but if you turn on the lights, it's no big deal.
你是什么意思？
What's your point?
我的意思是 你应该打电话给你儿子
My point is, you should call your son.
- 他要是不理我怎么办？- 至少你会知道
- What if he won't talk to me? - At least you'll know.
也就不必担心这件事了 也就不会再害怕了
Then you could stop worrying about it. You won't have to be afraid anymore.
我不管多生我爸的气 总会跟他讲话的 特别是在过节的时候
No matter how mad I was, I'd talk to my dad. Especially around the holidays.
我不知道
I don't know.
你试一试吧 就算是为了你的孙女
Just give it a shot. For your granddaughter anyway.
我保证她很想你和你的礼物
I'm sure she misses you. And the presents.
我寄过一张支票给她
I send her a check.
我希望我爷爷奶奶也寄支票给我 他们总是寄衣服给我
I wish my grandparents did that. They always send me clothes.
去年就给了我一件上面织着大鸟的毛衣
Last year I got a sweater with a bird knitted on it.
啊 那不错啊
Oh, that's nice.
二年级的男生不适合穿那个
Not for a guy in the second grade.
要是穿了会被打的
You can get beat up for wearing something like that.
我一个朋友 因为听说他穿过…
I have a friend who got nailed…
有恐龙图案的睡衣 就被打了
…because there was a rumor he wore dinosaur pajamas.
你还是赶快回家吧 想想我对你说的话
You better run home where you belong. Think about what I said.
- 怎么样？- 好吧
- All right? - Okay.
跟你聊天真高兴
It's nice talking to you.
我也是
Nice talking to you.
- 你怎么办？- 我？
- What about you? - Me?
是 你和你儿子
Yeah. You and your son.
再看看吧
We'll see what happens.
圣诞快乐！
Merry Christmas.
这是我的房子 我必须保卫它！
This is my house. I have to defend it.
（战略计划图）
（柏油）
先过去看看 然后回来收拾卡车
We'll check it out. We can come back for the truck.
我们怎么进去？
How do we go in?
到后门去 也许他会让我们进去
We'll go to the back door. Maybe he'll let us in.
是的 他是个孩子 小孩子都傻
Yeah, he's a kid. Kids are stupid.
感谢主赐我营养的微波炉快餐
Bless this nutritious, microwaveable macaroni and cheese dinner…
并祝福那些低价卖东西的人们
…and the people who sold it on sale. Amen.
就这样 现在起不再害怕
This is it. Don't get scared now.
圣诞快乐 小子
Merry Christmas, little fella.
我们知道你在里面 而且只有你一个人
We know that you're in there and that you're all alone.
快点 小子 开门！
Yeah, come on, kid. Open up.
是圣诞老人和小精灵来啦
It's Santy Claus and his elf.
我们不会伤害你的
We won't hurt you.
不 不会的 我们还带了礼物来给你呢
No, no. Got some nice presents for you.
好孩子 来开门吧
Be a good little fella now and open the door.
怎么了？
What?
怎么了？怎么了？
What? What?
怎么了？
What?
- 怎么搞的？- 抓住那…
- What happened? - Get that little…
你好
Hello.
太好了！太好了！
Yes! Yes!
这兔崽子有枪！
The little jerk is armed!
好吧 我从前门进去 你从地下室进去
That's it! I'm going in the front. You go down the basement!
自作聪明！
That smart aleck!
这小兔崽子 死定了你
Oh, boy. That's it, you little… You little…
这次可不会了 你这个小兔崽子
No, not this time, you little brat.
小混蛋 你在哪？
You little creep, where are you?
干得好！
Yes!
我要把你的脑袋扯下来！
…rip his head off…
你死定了 小子
You're dead, kid.
小浑蛋 你在哪？
Where are you, you little creep?
哈利！我来了
Harry, I'm coming in!
噢 不 我真的好害怕！
Oh, no! I'm really scared.
太晚了 小子！我们已经在房子里 就要抓到你了！
It's too late for you, kid, we're in the house. We're gonna get you.
好吧！过来抓我吧！
Okay, come and get me!
你这个…
Why, you…
你死定了！
Now you're dead!
我非杀了那小子不可！
I'm gonna kill that kid!
- 马文 - 哈利！
- Marv. - Harry?
你干嘛脱鞋？
Why'd you take your shoes off?
你干嘛弄得像只鸡一样？
Why are you dressed like a chicken?
我在上面 你们两个白痴 快过来抓我呀！
I'm up here, you morons. Come and get me.
你们要投降还是要再来一点？
You guys give up, or are you thirsty for more?
小心头！
Heads up!
别担心 马文 我会帮你抓到他
Don't worry, Marv. I'll get him for you.
太棒了！
Yes!
他不过是个孩子 哈利 我们能抓到他的
He's only a kid, Harry. We can take him.
闭嘴！你看什么看？
Shut up, will you? What is it?
你缺牙了
You're missing some teeth.
是哪颗？我的金牙！
Where? It's my gold tooth.
我的金牙没了！我非杀了他不可！
My gold tooth. I'll kill him. I'll kill him!
你再用罐子打…
You bomb me with one more can, kid…
老子一定把你的小鸡鸡扯下来放在油锅里煎！
…and I'll snap off your cojones and boil them in motor oil!
911紧急专线
911 emergency.
喂 有人在我家行窃
Hello, my house is being robbed.
地址是林肯大道656号 我的名字叫墨菲
My address is 656 Lincoln Boulevard. My name is Murphy.
不知道上面有什么东西
You never know what's there.
他在那里！
There he is!
抓到你了！我抓到他了！哈利！
I got you! I got him, Harry.
抓到了！
I got him.
哈利 快起来 帮我！
Harry, give me a hand!
我抓到他了
I got him!
哈利 帮我一把！快起来呀！
Harry, help me. Get up!
我抓到他了！
I got him.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
哈利 不要动！
Harry, don't move.
马文？
Marv?
不要动！
Don't move.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
打死了吗？
Did I get him?
在哪里？在哪里？
Where is it? Where is it?
别管它 爽了没有？你这个浑蛋
Never mind that. Here! How do you like it, huh? You jerk!
快去抓那个小孩！快去！抓住他！
Get that kid, before I… Get that kid!
跑哪去了？
Where'd he go?
说不定自杀了吧
Maybe he committed suicide.
在下面！你们两个大坏蛋 来抓我呀 要不然我报警了！
Down here, you big horse's ass! Come get me before I call the police.
- 我去把这小子抓来！- 等等
- Let's get him! - Wait, wait.
这小子就是要我们…
It's just what he wants us to do:
从楼下过去中他的机关！想狠狠修理我们
Go back through his fun house so we get all tore up.
他就要报警了！
He's gonna call the cops!
在树屋怎么报警？
From a tree house?
过去
Come on.
从窗户过去？
Out the window?
我可不行
I'm not going out the window.
怎么？你害怕了？你是不是怕了？
Why, you scared? Are you afraid? Come on, get out here.
快点啦你
Come on.
快点啦
Come on!
- 快点！- 哈利 还是回去吧
- Come on. Keep going. - Let's go back, Harry.
马文！别叫啦！
Shut it, Marv.
你好！
Hey, guys!
再看看这个！
Check this out.
快回去！快回去！
Go back. Go back.
他在那里！
There he is!
我要去报警！
Hey, I'm calling the cops!
等等 他就是想我们跟着他
Wait, wait! He wants us to follow him.
看我的 这边走
I got a better idea. Come on.
嗨 兄弟
Hi, pal.
这回栽在我们手里了吧 过来吧你
We outsmarted you this time. Get over here!
我们怎么修理他？
What are you gonna do?
以牙还牙
I'll do exactly what he did to us.
我要用喷灯烧他的头！
Burn his head with a blowtorch.
我要用熨斗烫他的脸！
I'll smash his face with an iron.
再用油漆桶往他的脸上摔！
I'd like to slap him in the face with a paint can!
要不就把钉子插到脚掌里去！
Shove a nail through his foot!
把他的小嫩手指一根一根咬下来 一次咬一根
I'm gonna bite off every one of these little fingers, one at a time.
快走 快回家去
Come on. Let's get you home.
哇！这下可好了！
Wow, this is great.
做得很好 每次做案都放水
Nice move, leaving the water running.
现在知道了 有水的房子就是你们干的
Now we know each and every house that you've hit.
找你们两个很久了
We've been looking for you guys for a long time.
好啊 记住了 我们就是有名的「水盗」
Yeah. Well, remember, we're the Wet Bandits.
- 我们就是水盗 就是流水的水… - 闭嘴！上车！
- Wet Bandits, that's W-E-T… - Shut up! Get in the car!
快点！
Hey, come on. Come on.
- 别碰我的头 朋友 - 上车！
- Hands off the head, pal! - Come on.
我不是个好母亲 不是好母亲
I'm a bad parent. I'm a bad parent.
不 你是个好母亲
No, you're not.
你太自责了
You're beating yourself up there.
这是常有的事
These things happen.
要是说起不称职的父母 看看我们吧
You want to talk about bad parents? Look at us.
我们一年中有48到49个星期在外巡回演出 几乎见不到家人
We're on the road 48, 49 weeks a year. We hardly see our families.
那边的乔治…
Joe, over there. Gosh, you know…
不记得自己孩子的名字
…he forgets his kids' names half the time.
那边的兹吉根本就还没见过自己的孩子呢
Ziggy over there, he's never even met his kid.
还有艾迪 他对不起家里的事就更多了
Eddy… Let's just hope none of them write a book about him.
你们有因为去度假 把孩子忘在家里吗？
Tell me, have you gone on vacation and left your child home?
没有
No.
但是我倒是有一次把孩子忘在殡仪馆了
But I did leave one at a funeral parlor once.
那也是同样让人很难受
Yeah, it was terrible too. I was all distraught and everything.
我和我太太把孩子留在殡仪馆了
The wife and I, we left the little tyke there in the funeral parlor.
孩子被忘在殡仪馆里整整一天 到了晚上…
All day. You know, we went back at night, when we…
才想起他来 我们赶紧去找他
…came to our senses, there he was.
他在遗体旁待了整整一天
Apparently, he was there all day with a corpse.
六七个星期之后 他就好了 你知道的…
He was okay. You know, after six, seven weeks.
就又说又蹦又跳了
He came around and started talking again.
小孩子很快就恢复了 不像大人那样
They get over it. Kids are resilient like that.
我们或许不应该谈论这个话题
We shouldn't talk about this.
- 我只是想让你振作起来 - 对不起
- I was just trying to cheer you up. - I'm sorry I did.
妈！
Mom?
妈？
凯文！
Kevin!
圣诞快乐！宝贝
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
凯文 妈妈真的对不起你
Oh, Kevin, I'm so sorry.
其他人都去哪了？
Where's everybody else?
噢 他们回不来
Oh, baby, they couldn't come.
他们是想回来的…
They wanted to so much…
我才没有流口水呢！有吗？
I didn't fall asleep in the back and drool all over you, did I?
- 你流了 - 别吵了
- You do drool! - Shut up!
凯文 你还好吧？
Kevin, my boy. How are you? It's good to see you.
你没事吧
You're all right.
我爱你 你还好吗？
I love you. You okay?
凯文
Hey, Kev.
你还没把房子给烧了 真是了不起
It's cool that you didn't burn the place down.
谢谢 巴兹
Thanks, Buzz.
等一下 你们是怎么回来的？
Wait a minute. How'd you guys get home?
我们坐的是你不愿意等的那班飞机
On the morning flight you didn't want to wait for.
- 喔！谢谢 - 圣诞快乐！
- Oh, no. Thank you. - Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐！
Merry Christmas.
谁去找间开门的商店
Someone has to find an open store.
我昨天去店里买了
I went shopping yesterday.
你？买东西？
You, shopping?
我买了牛奶 买了鸡蛋 还有柔软精
I got some milk, eggs and fabric softener.
- 什么？- 真的假的？
- What? - No kidding?
这孩子还真好玩
What a funny guy.
我们不在家的时候你还做了什么？
What else did you do while we were away?
只是在屋里东摸西摸
Just hung around.
把东西拿上楼
Bring your stuff upstairs.
买东西？他连自己的鞋带都不会绑 还会买东西？
Shopping? He doesn't know how to tie his shoe. He's going shopping?
凯文才不会这么做呢
This is not the Kevin I knew.
宝贝 这是什么东西？
Honey, what's this?
凯文！看你把我的房间搞成什么样子？
Kevin! What did you do to my room?